Meeker Family Papers, 1721-1950 Ms 41
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Meeker Family Papers, 1721-1950
Ms 41
Fairfield Museum and History Center
0.25 Linear feet (1 box, 70 items, 1 oversize item)
Meeker family
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
John Meeker (d. 1722) settled in Fairfield, CT in the late 1600's. The Meekers in this collection lived in Fairfield, Westport and Southport. W. B. Meeker (1788-1862) was in the shipping and mercantile business in Southport. His son, W. B. Meeker, Jr. (1829-1915), became a business partner with his father. His daughter Emily Meeker (1821-1911) lived in Southport, CT.
Scope and Contents note
The collection is housed in one box and made up of three folders and one oversize item. The deeds are arranged by date in Folder A as are the bills and bills receipted in Folder B. Folder C contains Oliver H. Meeker's day book and Emily Meeker's autograph book. The oversize item is the Meeker family Bible which is kept at Ogeden House in season.
Meeker, W. B. (Wakeman B.), 1829-1915; Meeker, Emily, 1821-1911; Meeker, Oliver H., d. 1948; Meeker, W. B. (Wakeman B.), 1788-1862; Account books--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Deeds--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Deeds--Connecticut--Southport; Farmers--Connecticut; Merchants--Connecticut--Southport.; Probate records--Connecticut--Fairfield; Probate records--Connecticut--Southport; Receipts(financial records); Wills.; Writs--Connecticut.
- Legal Papers, 1721-1950; Folder A; 15 items
  - Deed from Joseph Jackson to Nathan Meeker, 1736
  - Deed from Stephen Jackson to Nathan Meeker, 1740
  - Deed from Thomas Phillips to Seth Meeker, 1788
  - Deed from Stephen and Abigail Hurlbut to Eunice Meeker, 1800
  - Deed from Thomas Wheeler to Daniel Meeker, III, 1804
  - Agreement between John Meeker and Samuel Jennings, 1726
  - Bond from Nathan Meeker to Moses Jackson, 1726
  - Probate papers and will of John Meaker, 1721, 1727, n.d.; 3 items
  - Probate papers of Daniel Meeker, 1817
  - Probate papers of Oliver H. Meeker, 1948, 1950; 2 items
  - Writ, David Meaker vs. John Sherwood with payment, 1788; 2 items
- Bills and Bills Receipted, 1835-1892; Folder B; 48 items
  - D. H. Meeker, 1884-1886; 8 items
  - Oliver Meeker, 1882-1892; 24 items
  - W. B. Meeker, 1835
  - W. B. Meeker and Son, 1878; 16 items
- Books, Folder B; 3 items
  - Oliver H. Meeker's day book, Greenfield Hill and out of town (investments, commodities, dry goods and farm help at end of book, 1885), 1866-1874
  - Emily O. Meeker's autograph book, 1843
    Custodial History note
    Gift of George O. Pratt.
- Meeker Bible, 1712; Oversize Item A